# Suheyl Enis Aras

518-961-70-35 | arasenis@gmail.com | linkedin.com/in/enis-aras | github.com/enisaras

### **OVERVIEW**

Driven STEM student with a Bachelor's degree in Computer Science and a Fall 2023 candidate for M.S in Applied Mathematics at Rensselaer Polytechnic Institute. Experienced in machine learning, data analysis and software development through schoolwork, research and contract work. Future career interests include software engineering, data scientist and quantitative finance analyst.

#### EDUCATION

# Rensselaer Polytechnic Instute

Troy, NY

Bachelor of Science in Computer Science, Minor in Finance, GPA: 3.3

Fall 2020 - August 2022

- Learned about topics related to algorithms including dynamic programming, divide and conquer, NP-completeness and graph theory and designed many algorithms aimed to solve real life problems.
- Learned about the essential aspects of programming languages, including theoretical foundations such as the lambda calculus, the actor model, and first-order logic. Used a variety of programming languages which included Haskell, Erlang and Prolog to demonstrate ability of these theoretical foundations of computer science and compare how each language is used to solve common programming problems.
- Learned the foundations and mathematics behind and implemented many various machine learning algorithms including linear regression, deep neural networks, K-Means clustering and spectral clustering.

# EXPERIENCE

### Undergrad Research Assistant at Hamad Bin Khalifa University

January 2022 – May 2022

Doha, Qatar

Part Time

- Collects financial data and performs exploratory data analysis.
- Develops deep reinforcement learning models using the python programming language and various packages.
- Implements various other machine learning models and compares results to the reinforcement learning models.
- Writes an academic research paper to be published at a local scientific magazine.

# Algo Developer at Quantify

November 2020 – August 2021

Remote, NY

- Contract• Worked with clients to convert their existing trading strategies into algorithms that can be automatically traded using platforms like QuantConnect and Alpaca using Python and C# programming languages.
  - Visualized many trading strategies and back tested them using the platform TradingView and their scripting language PineScript.

# Projects

#### **DJ Reco** | Python, Tensorflow, Spotify Web API

- A chat bot that recommends music using the Spotify API according to the users previous interests, mood and more.
- Uses the Python tenserflow package to run various machine learning algorithms including K-Means clustering and Neural Networks.
- Features a gigantic database of songs and a sound analysis for each one to help make accurate recommendations.

#### Reinforcement Learning on Equity Trading | Python, Tenserflow

- Uses a variety of equity data including stocks and cryptocurrency to trade according to predictions made by various types of reinforcement learning algorithms.
- Features a full trading environment and uses the tenserflow library to run the various reinforcement learning algorithms.

# TECHNICAL SKILLS

Languages: Python(Expert), C/C++(Intermediate), SQL(Intermediate), JavaScript(Expert), Java(Intermediate)

Frameworks: React, Node.js, Django

Developer Tools: Git, TravisCI, Amazon Web Services, Linux

Libraries: Pandas, NumPv, Matplotlib, Selenium, TenserFlow, Sci-kit learn

Other: Linear Algebra, Problem Solving, Multivariable Calculus, Data Visualization, Data Analysis